<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Your Site's RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is Natanael's Portfolio Site]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:59:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[API design and remote working productivity]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learning about remote work from APIs]]></description><link>https://www.natslabs.com/blog/apis-remote-work</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.natslabs.com/blog/apis-remote-work</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this article I&amp;#39;ve set out to explore how API design can relate to remote work. I didn&amp;#39;t know where I would land before starting to write about it, but I&amp;#39;m happy with where this exploration got me. I wrote my learnings at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Going one layer up&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote work mirrors in-office work fairly well, but communication is one aspect that loses  nuance. Whatever doesn’t fit in the data cable must stay behind, for better or for worse. Since smoke signals, you can reach far but there is only so much you can say. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machines need to do remote work almost all of the time, often with other systems which are complete strangers, without using tone of voice, body language, or facial expressions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there any lessons we can take from how machines communicate? Maybe the most important one that we can apply to remote working is to &lt;b&gt;be as intentional as you can&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What are APIs?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;APIs are one way computers can show up remotely for work. They stand for Application Programming Interfaces. You can use APIs yourself to talk with a computer, but more importantly to get many computers to work with each other. Jeff Lawson, formerly from the messaging company Twilio, has written a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twilio.com/blog/ask-your-developer-a-playbook-available-now&quot;&gt;very approachable book&lt;/a&gt; introducing them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He uses banking as an example in the book. “Nowadays your bank is a mobile app and you like your bank if the software is fast, if it is bug free and if they regularly update it with new features and functionality that makes your life better”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;APIs are shaping business models. You can now put a whole company - with hundreds, thousands of people - behind a set of APIs. APIs can very quickly be improved on in the background, served to many users and even get piped to other APIs. Here are examples from &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.stripe.com/api&quot;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; and from &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.dev/docs/api&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt; (I’m not associated with them). These recipe books with sharp technical commands don&amp;#39;t need UI updates, language translations or you to commute to a location for them to work. Each API section could be maintained by one or multiple teams, changed many times a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Examples&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.stripe.com/api/balance&quot;&gt;Stripe balance&lt;/a&gt; : GET /v1/balance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.dev/docs/api/admin-rest/2024-07/resources/customer#get-customers?ids=207119551,1073339474&quot;&gt;list of your Shopify customers&lt;/a&gt;:  GET /admin/api/2024-07/customers.json&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To handle internet volume and shopper&amp;#39;s little patience for slow experiences, we need standardisation - whatever doesn’t fit in the API pipe must stay behind, for better or for worse. When you use smoke signals to signal danger to your tribe, attacks to your army, or a new pope, the ones receiving the message already know what it means from a preset list of answers. That&amp;#39;s how you scale communications with APIs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Talking to other machines for fun and learnings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time for a practical example. We’ll use your phone to get a custom notification using the same internet verbs that APIs use and adapt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://ntfy.sh/&quot;&gt;ntfy&lt;/a&gt; on your phone for this part. (I’m not associated with them) This will let you receive push notifications for free on your phone. It&amp;#39;s free to use on public channels - for our purposes it&amp;#39;s perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of a title for your channel. I’m picking chocolate_chip_pancake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst I’m working on embedding this, you can still try it in a very simple app I built &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.linklyhq.com/l/1l8Ef&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Now make sure the title/topic is spelled the same way, and fire away! Sure enough, you will be able to receive your first ever self-made notification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The code for the app is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NatMota/natslabs-ntfy-demo/blob/main/flask_app.py&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;!WARNING! The app is not really using an API call! APIs themselves simplify and hide other tools that enable their job. For this app, the more low level tool being used to send a request to ntfy is &lt;b&gt;&lt;code&gt;cURL.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cURL&lt;/code&gt; takes care of delivering the message efficiently and securely, then showing you the server&amp;#39;s reply. Connected software everywhere makes use of these lower level tools to work. In this case, the ntfy server does the rest of the work of piping that message to your phone as a notification. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can try this code yourself in a terminal:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -d &amp;quot;It’s pancake time! 🥞&amp;quot; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ntfy.sh/chocolate_chip_pancake&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ntfy.sh/chocolate_chip_pancake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-d specifies there is data to be sent. There is more discussion of ntfy &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33517944&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Going one layer down&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do modern APIs look the way they look? Because they have evolved from a need of scale and security. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most successful approach to designing them is REST. It stands for &lt;b&gt;representational state transfer&lt;/b&gt;, which means there is a separation between the pancake notification you ask ntfy to send, the version of the message ntfy holds on their servers, and the one that shows up on your mobile phone. The message &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;It’s pancake time! 🥞&amp;quot; &lt;/code&gt;will be transcribed many times before arriving on your phone&amp;#39;s notification center. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why REST? Because REST promotes a cookie cutter approach to making API requests that is highly approachable no matter what programming language you decide on using. The formatting also uses very well known conventions, in REST&amp;#39;s case the HTTP standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) is the grammar of choice for web-scale data format and transfer. The intention to use it for scale means HTTP doesn&amp;#39;t just apply to websites! The cURL tool above is one way to transfer data using the HTTP protocol and a good way to test APIs manually. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What patterns do you see between &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/docs/api&quot;&gt;Stripe’s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://shopify.dev/docs/api&quot;&gt;Shopify’s&lt;/a&gt; examples? As you look through the functionality, notice how they don’t promise the whole world, but very specific, targeted and regimented operations to help you use their service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The HTTP actions used are linked to elemental data changes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;p&gt;Action&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods/GET&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; method requests a representation of the specified resource. Requests using &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; should only retrieve data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods/POST&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; method submits an entity to the specified resource, often causing a change in state or side effects on the server. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods/PUT&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;PUT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;PUT&lt;/code&gt; method replaces all current representations of the target resource with the request payload. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods/DELETE&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;DELETE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;DELETE&lt;/code&gt; method deletes the specified resource. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find 4-5 other less used actions &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Methods&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. They are called request methods because a &amp;#39;server&amp;#39; like the ntfy server gets requests from another computer, like ours, which it acts on. They are also called verbs. Our computer started the discussion so it is called the client in this case, but we could make it listen to requests too and make it act as a server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Designing REST APIs in very brief terms&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;APIs are can be judged on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;code instructions you use to operate the machine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;the response the machine gives to instructions, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;quality of human-focused documentation - so long as it is not a crutch for using the API&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skipping the very interesting background, API experiences can be judged by:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;how self contained the information in each request and response is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;how clear and predictable an instruction is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;how much separation there is between the business logic the requester can use and the underlying data structures the responder is working with&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;how quality\satisfaction is perceived by users based on &lt;b&gt;external attributes&lt;/b&gt; of the system&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;speed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;power and precision of instructions available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;usability of API server responses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are maturity models for this, which have matured 🧐 over the years. Importantly, as raised in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/281287283_A_Maturity_Model_for_Semantic_RESTful_Web_APIs&quot;&gt;(Salvadori &amp;amp; Siqueira, 2015)&lt;/a&gt;, all of these are subjective! Each API has different needs and goals. My product spidey sense is tingling and triggering a mantra that has become really &amp;#39;loud&amp;#39; lately: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;TALK TO YOUR F****** CUSTOMERS! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s get to the pretty models in a bit and take some learnings from a standout achievement of the British government: its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/government-digital-service&quot;&gt;Digital Service&lt;/a&gt;. These are their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/gds-api-technical-and-data-standards&quot;&gt;tips for API design&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start with your customer&amp;#39;s needs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check for existing APIs and reuse or expand them if you can&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your API before the system powering it so you prioritise &lt;b&gt;user experience&lt;/b&gt;, API &lt;b&gt;self sufficiency&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;separation of business logic &lt;/b&gt;from internal system actions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write out an API specification i.e. following &lt;a href=&quot;https://swagger.io/specification/&quot;&gt;OpenAPI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test your assumptions with customers against the specification you wrote&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iterate on the design and decide what your live API will look like. It needs to be backwards compatible, so it&amp;#39;s much easier to iterate on it before it is published.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving from there into the principles REST was &lt;a href=&quot;https://ics.uci.edu/~fielding/pubs/dissertation/rest_arch_style.htm&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/a&gt; to meet:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;uniform interface – all API requests for the same resource should have the same uniform resource identifier (URI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;i.e. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.stripe.com/api/customers/update&quot;&gt;POST/ v1/ customers/ :id&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.stripe.com/api/customers/retrieve&quot;&gt;GET/ v1/ customers/ :id&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.stripe.com/api/customers/delete&quot;&gt;DELETE/ v1/ customers/ :id&lt;/a&gt; are all uniform calls on the &amp;#39;customer&amp;#39; resource to create, get information on, and delete a customer with a specific id&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;they are self descriptive if you are familiar with HTTP verbs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;they represent the customer resource, but they are not for example the actual database entry for the customer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;the server responses should be uniform too. for example, the GET response should let the client know how to retrieve the full list of Stripe customers if you remove the id filter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;client and server – these must be independent of each other and separated by a &lt;b&gt;well defined interface&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;statelessness – this means the client knows everything needed to operate on the server in one request, and so does the server. This means more cumputers running the server software can be added behind an API to scale the service without having to share context previous client requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cacheable – resources should be cached on the client side and server side, to improve performance and scalability. Caching is when you store information you already know. This saves resources and optimises for scaling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;layered system – allows for security and scaling services to be placed between the client and the server, to make the service more reliable and secure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shiny maturity model time: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richardson_Maturity_Model&quot;&gt;Richardson&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; - level based approach &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 0 - anything can be requested, you cannot predict how to use the API without extensive docs, doesn&amp;#39;t qualify as RESTful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /bookingService	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; POST	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; retrieve destinations/hotels/rooms; add/cancel a reservation; etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 1 - general resources are introduced and can be grouped with common sense, it&amp;#39;s still not restful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /bookingReservations	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; POST	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; 
add/cancel reservations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /bookingDestinations	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; POST	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; retrieve destinations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 2 - HTTP verbs added - further specialising the resource and narrowing down the outcome of each action, partially RESTful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /reservations	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; GET	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; get reservations according to certain criteria&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /reservations	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; POST	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; add/cancel reservations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level 3 - response includes links to other actions you can take on a resource, a bit like how the &amp;#39;See Also&amp;#39; section on wikipedia works for humans. fully RESTful because these links should be everything the client needs to navigate the API without the need for documentation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;URI:&lt;/b&gt; /room	&lt;b&gt;HTTP:&lt;/b&gt; GET	&lt;b&gt;Actions:&lt;/b&gt; get room information according to specific filtering&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Response:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;code&gt;{   
   customerId: &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,
   reservations: [{room: &amp;quot;102&amp;quot;, checkin: &amp;quot;10-11-2020&amp;quot;, checkout: &amp;quot;11-14-2020&amp;quot;, price: &amp;quot;100&amp;quot;, href: &amp;quot;https://localhost:8080/room/102&amp;quot;}]
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code&gt;href &lt;/code&gt;is a link to more information about room 102. This is useful because then the client code can be adapted to make more probing requests if needed. This can also be useful to help get more information about error responses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algermissen.io/classification_of_http_apis.html&quot;&gt;CoHA&lt;/a&gt; - strict focus on Level 3 above to describe the ideal REST state only. The key features are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identification of Resources&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manipulation of Resources through Representations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Self-Descriptive Messages	&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hypermedia as the Engine of Application State&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;With 4. the API provides information in a way that guides the client through the application. The client starts with a basic entry point (like a URL) and gets responses with links and instructions on what to do next. The client uses these instructions to decide how to interact with the service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also covers the impact of REST on functional properties:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network Performance: Coarse grained, document oriented messages are encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network Efficiency: Visibility enables caching which improves network efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visibility: Messages are self-describing and can be &lt;b&gt;understood by intermediaries&lt;/b&gt;. This is the foundation for caching and trust i.e. firewall admins can understand the messages and allow exactly the traffic they want to let through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evolvability: Coupling between client and server is removed, server owners need not know about client particularities to evolve the servers without breaking clients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extensibility: Increased by loose coupling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simplicity: Maximized by uniformity of connectors and identifiers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scalability: Message self-descriptiveness constraint mandates message statelessness which in turn mandates the stateless server constraint. The latter guarantees scalibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initial cost: Considerably high learning curve, cost of proper media type design, highest client side effort (burdon of loose coupling is placed on client side programming model)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maintenance cost:Low due to simplicity, easy to find knowledgeable staff. (While it is considerable effort to design a proper media type, understanding it has a low entry barrier)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evolution cost: REST optimizes for evolvability. Server owners need not consider impact of evolution on clients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/281287283_A_Maturity_Model_for_Semantic_RESTful_Web_APIs&quot;&gt;(Salvadori &amp;amp; Siqueira, 2015)&lt;/a&gt; - explain the domain and data even better so that the api&amp;#39;s self referencing can guide a software agent &lt;i&gt;at runtime, &lt;/i&gt;as opposed to a human at client design time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a time where automated agents may become widely successful, this angle is very interesting. For day to day operations with this next generation of API, a software agent would not need to think anymore, only act directly on their goal. With initial exceptions, this approach may need only minima; error handling - all actions in the system are predetermined. This comes with the heavy price of having to think very hard through the domain about what flows should be standardised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even with the new proposed maturity dimensions of:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;data: understandability and discoverability&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;profile: context and recommended domain-specific recipes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;mapping a business outcome to a range of very intensive and very precise operations will still be very important for the value of the API. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where were we?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right, how to apply API design to working remotely. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two things are apparent when you pick up the phone line to talk to another person - you probably wont be able to work faster, and its not really the same as being there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When everyone is on a multiplex line, the plot thickens. You still can’t talk or chat over other people. Whatever communication is happening human to human, is done in a sequential and stateful way. And humans process information in a sequential way too. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you apply some principles of API design, you can make yourself, your team and your professional network work more effectively. The trick is to standardise the right interactions which you can do at volume, and letting go of more ‘genuine’ dimensions. So maybe you can&amp;#39;t duplicate yourself, but you can use documents, shape how information flows to your team, and shape your organisation itself so remote work can be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also seems not all work needs to be optimised this way. Solo working is mostly fine. But colaboration is where this is more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The point of APIs is that while they can be complex and have many functions, they should not be complicated to use. An API that takes a long time to implement is not a great API. There will always be a competitor around the corner with better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Making remote work more deliberate&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, here are some API design rules of thumb that have interesting parallels to repetitive work and working remotely in a distributed way. Could you collaborate effectively with another human in a completely different timezone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Planning - API planning planning is always the most important step.  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know what your goal is? How often do you review it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This month?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know what kind of work you will not do? Or delegate?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are your boundaries well defined?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there any upcoming events that will affect your capacity to help effectively?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Clear communication - API &amp;#39;contracts&amp;#39; clearly define how they can be used and don&amp;#39;t hide inconsistent behavior&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can you communicate more clearly?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can you communicate more regularly?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How connected and informed do your teammates feel?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Collaboration and support - APIs often require collaboration between different teams or organisations to develop, maintain, and support them.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know your teammate’s goals?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know their preferred way of collaborating?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know how best to contribute to shared goals?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Documentation - A well-designed API must have clear, concise, and easily understood documentation to enable developers to integrate with it effectively.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you have a guide to how best to deal with yourself?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managers in tech often create ‘readme’ files, but you don’t have to be one to create yours. Some examples &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypercontext.com/blog/management-skills/49-manager-readmes&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is your self documentation, your team’s documentation, and your organization’s documentation clear?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you have guidelines?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you keep your documentation fresh? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Standardization - Consistent API design patterns, naming conventions, and error handling make it easier for developers to understand and use the API.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How well do you know your tools of the trade?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you aware of how you can update them in the future?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you comfortable with all of them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you apply your tools, methods and processes consistently?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scalability and performance - Good API design accounts for scalability and performance, ensuring that the API can handle growing numbers of users and data without degradation in quality.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can you scale a team and maintain performance?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the tradeoffs there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How should you set goals for teams to promote collaboration?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What parts of your work are repetitive? Which ones may no longer be needed?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Work empathetically and testing&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;b&gt;A well-designed API should be easy to use and understand, minimising developer friction and promoting adoption.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What assumptions am I making by communicating or acting this way?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What happened the last time someone was confused with something I said?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are communicating a new concept, method or to a new audience, how often do you test it first?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Flexibility and adaptability - A successful API should be able to evolve and adapt to changing requirements and technology trends without disrupting existing users.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you introduce a new process, what do you keep the same?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you plan for change?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are there existing ‘building blocks’ you could keep the same, instead of redoing it from scratch?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are your processes and communication fault tolerant? Do they forgive genuine or systemic mistakes like cognitive biases?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Leverage your network! APIs are more powerful when they are connected together&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know what skills there are on your network?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How often do you leverage your network?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does your network serve a purpose?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you see potential links in your network you could make happen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;And lastly, know when doing something in person would be more effective, if you have that luxury! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>